<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>India Tourism</title>
	<atom:link href="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:16:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/cropped-aged-ancient-antique-2181887-e1675430564527-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>India Tourism</title>
	<link>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>North-East India- Paradise On Earth</title>
		<link>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/north-east-india-paradise-on-earth/</link>
					<comments>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/north-east-india-paradise-on-earth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/?p=659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[North East India is blessed with scenic natural beauty, rich biodiversity, rare wild life, historical sites, distinct cultural and ethnic heritage and warm and welcoming people. The region offers unforgettable visits for tourists interested in wild life, religious, cultural and ethnic tourism, river cruises and great scope for mountaineering, trekking. Northeast of India is home &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/north-east-india-paradise-on-earth/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">North-East India- Paradise On Earth</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>North East India is blessed with scenic natural beauty, rich biodiversity, rare wild life, historical sites, distinct cultural and ethnic heritage and warm and welcoming people. The region offers unforgettable visits for tourists interested in wild life, religious, cultural and ethnic tourism, river cruises and  great scope for mountaineering, trekking. Northeast of India is home to many wildlife sanctuaries like Kaziranga National Park famous for the one horned rhinoceros, Manas National Park, Nameri, Orang, Namdhapha in Arunachal Pradesh, Balpakram in Meghalaya, Keibul Namjao in Manipur, Intanki in Nagaland, Khangchendzonga in Sikkim. The mighty Brahmaputra flows through the length of Assam where tourists can enjoy memorable river cruises and the flowing rivers of Arunachal Pradesh which feed the Brahmaputra offering incredible white water rafting experiences.</p>



<p></p>



<h4><strong>Arunachal Pradesh(Must Visit Places)</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong><u>Tawang</u></strong>– Tawang situated at an elevation of 3048 mt. in northwestern part of Arunachal Pradesh, it is home to the Tawang Monastery which is the second largest and oldest in Asia. The monastery is three stories high and is enclosed by a 282 mt. long compound wall. There are many other places of interest like Sela Pass, Jang Waterfalls, PTSO Lake etc.</li>



<li><strong><u>Ziro</u></strong>– A picturesque town in Lower Subansiri district, it is home to the Apatani tribe. Famous for gentle pine clad hills and rice fields it also hosts the popular Ziro Music Festival in September every year. Ziro is also included as in India&#8217;s Tentative List for UNESCO&#8217;s World Heritage Site.</li>



<li><strong><u>Mechuka</u></strong>– also known as Menchukha, is a small picturesque town nestled at 1829 mt. in West Siang District. Menchukha is situated in a forested valley, surrounded by pine trees and thornbushes with the river Yargyapchu flowing through the valley.</li>



<li><strong><u>Pasighat</u></strong>– Is the oldest town of Arunachal Pradesh founded in 1911 A.D. by the British. The Brahmaputra emerges from the foothills of Pasighat under the name of Dihang or Siang.</li>
</ul>



<h4><strong>Assam (Must Visit Places)</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Kaziranga National Park</strong>– A World Heritage Site, the park hosts two-thirds of the world’s Great One-horned rhinoceros and also boasts of the highest density of tigers among the protected areas in the world and was declared a Tiger Reserve in 2706.</li>



<li><strong>Kamakhya Temple</strong> – A famous Hindu temple dedicated to the mother goddess Kamakhya. It is one of the oldest of the 51 Shakti Pithas. Situated on the Nilachal Hill in western part of Guwahati.</li>



<li><strong>Brahmaputra River</strong>– Is one of the major rivers of Asia and is a trans-boundary river flowing through China, India and Bangladesh.</li>
</ul>



<h4><strong>Manipur(Must Visit Places)</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Loktak Lake </strong>– 48 Km/s. from Imphal, it is the largest fresh water lake in the North East Region. Small islands that are actually floating weeds on which the Lake-dwellers live in the backdrop of the shimmering blue water of the Lake, labyrinthine boat routes and colourful water plants.</li>



<li><strong>Moirang&nbsp;</strong>&#8211; Situated near the Loktak Lake, this town is one of the main centres of early Meitei folk culture and has a special place in the history of the Indian Freedom struggle as it was at Moirang that the flag of the Indian National Army was first unfurled on April 14, 1944 and has an INA Museum containing letters, photographs, badges of ranks and other memorabilia of the sacrifices made by the INA under the leadership of Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Khwairamband Bazar/ Ima Market</strong>&#8211; A unique all women&#8217;s market, having 3,000 or more &#8220;Imas&#8221; or mothers who run the stalls. It is split into two sections on either side of a road. Vegetables, fruits, fishes and household groceries are sold on one side and exquisite handlooms and household tools on the other.</li>
</ul>



<h4><strong>Meghalaya(Must Visit Places)</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Shillong&nbsp;</strong>– The State Capital of Meghalaya is also known as the “Scotland of the East” because of the rolling hills around the town. Shillong has steadily grown in size since it was made the civil station of the Khasi and Jaintia Hills in 1864 by the British. Shillong remained the capital of undivided Assam until the creation of the new state of Meghalaya on 21 January 1972. In 2016 it was voted &#8220;India&#8217;s Favourite Hill Station&#8221; by HolidayIQ.com.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Cherrapunji</strong> &#8211; The historic name Sohra is now more commonly used. It is credited as being the wettest place on Earth, but nearby Mawsynram currently holds that record.</li>



<li><strong>Mawlynnong</strong>&nbsp;&#8211; Is a village in the East Khasi Hills district about 90 km/s from Shillong and is famous for its cleanliness and natural attraction. Mawlynnong was awarded the prestigious tag of &#8216;Cleanest Village in Asia&#8217; in 2703 by Discover India Magazine.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Dawki&nbsp;</strong>– A border town with Bangladesh, it has the beautiful Umngot River as a major tourist attraction.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Mawphlang Sacred Grove</strong> – One of the most famous sacred forests preserved by traditional religious sanction about 25 kilometers from Shillong . The sacred grove has an amazing life form of plants, flowering trees, orchids and butterflies. An ideal destination for nature lovers. </li>
</ul>



<h4><strong>Mizoram(Must Visit Places)</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Aizawl&nbsp;</strong>– The state capital, is situated at about 1132 mt/s. above sea level and is a bustling city set on ridges of steep hills. It is air linked by daily flights from Kolkata and Guwahati. It is also connected to Imphal by air and is accessible from Shillong, Guwahati and Silchar by road.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Thenzawl</strong>&#8211; A village located at a distance of 43 km/s from Aizawl. The Tropic of Cancer runs through this picturesque village. It is an important centre of traditional Mizo handloom industry and produce rich and colorful varieties of handlooms.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Hmuifang</strong>&nbsp;&#8211; With an elevation of 1619 metres, is covered with virgin forests reserved since the days of the Mizo chiefs..&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Vantawng Falls</strong> &#8211; located at a distance of about 137 km/s from Aizawl, it is the highest and most spectacular of all the waterfalls in Mizoram.</li>
</ul>



<h4><strong>Nagaland(Must Visit Places)</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Khonoma</strong>&nbsp;– A historic village located about 20 km from the state capital Kohima it is recordede to have resisted British rule in the region from 1830s to 1880 and etched its name into the history of Indian resistance to the colonial invasion.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Wokha</strong>&nbsp;– Home of the Lotha tribes is a land of beautiful mountain ranges and rivers and is known for its vibrant dances and folk songs. Wokha literally means Census in Lotha. It was a place where Lothas counted heads before spreading out into the villages during their waves of migration.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Pfutsero&nbsp;</strong>– A picturesque town in Phek district is the highest altitude town and the coldest inhabited place in Nagaland with temperatures dropping to below zero in winters. The Baptist Theological College in Pfutsero is one of the oldest in Nagaland. The best time to visit is from mid-October (harvesting time) to April. One can also take a day trip to Khezhakeno Village, a very important village in the context of the Naga history. It is said that the first Nagas stayed at this village before moving on to other parts of Nagaland.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Mokokchung</strong> – Home of the Ao tribe and is the culturally nerve centre of the Ao people. Tourist attractions in Mokokchung, which are great places to visit, are Longkhum, Mopungchuket, and Ungma.</li>
</ul>



<h4><strong>Sikkim(Must Visit Places)</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Gangtok</strong>&#8211; The capital city of Sikkim is located on a ridge at a height of 5500 feet. With a spectacular view of the Khangchendzonga, the town provides the perfect base for travel through the state. Gangtok is a cosmopolitan town which offers the tourists all possible amenities.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Changu Lake&nbsp;</strong>&#8211; 38 km from Gangtok and at an altitude of 12,400 ft, the ethereally beautiful Tsomgo (Changu) lake is a must on every visitors itinerary. A winding road through rugged mountain terrain and sharp cliffs takes you to Tsomgo, which means source of the water in Bhutia language. The lake derives its water from the melting snows of the mountains surrounding the lake. Of legendary beauty, the lake looks different at different seasons. In winter the placid lake remains frozen with the area around it covered in snow while in late spring the profusion of flowers in bloom adds a riot of colours around the lake.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Rumtek</strong>&#8211; Situated around 23 km/s from Gangtok, it is a quiet getaway and home to the Rumtek Monastery which is the largest monastery in Sikkim and demonstrates the best of Tibetan architecture.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Aritar </strong>&#8211; located in east Sikkim, Aritar is steeped in history and natural beauty. A breathtaking view of Khangchendzonga only adds to the many natural riches that Aritar is blessed with lush green forests, sweeping hills of paddy fields and placid lakes hidden inside deep forests makes it a perfect destination for those in search of nature trails and a serene holiday. The Aritar Gumpa is one of the oldest monasteries in Sikkim belonging to the Karma Kagyu lineage order of Tibetan Buddhism. </li>
</ul>



<h4><strong>Tripura(Must Visit Places)</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Ujjayanta Palace</strong> – The former royal palace of Tripura (princely state) situated in Agartala, the state capital of Tripura. The palace was constructed between 1899 and 1901 by the Tripura king, Maharaja Radha Kishore Manikya, and stands on the banks of a small lake surrounded by Mughal gardens.</li>



<li><strong>Tripura Sundari Temple</strong> – According to mythology, Lord Vishnu had cut off the body of Mata Sati into 51 pieces with his ‘Sudarshana Chakra’ and all these pieces fell at different places throughout the country and these places are known as ‘Shaktipeeths’.</li>



<li><strong>Rudrasagar Lake</strong>&nbsp;&#8211; About 55 km away from Agartala near Melaghar it is a 5.3 sq. km. water area. In the centre of the lake is the famous lake palace &#8220;Neermahal&#8221;. The lake witnesses a large number of migratory birds every winter.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Unakoti</strong>&nbsp;– About 178 km from Agartala, it dates back to 7th – 9th centuries if not earlier. The marvellous rock carvings, murals with their primitive beauty and waterfalls are great attractions. Unakoti means one less than a crore and t is said that these many rock cut carvings are available here. As per Hindu mythology, when Lord Shiva was going to Kashi along with one crore gods and goddesses he made a night halt at this location. He asked all the gods and goddesses to wake up before sun rise and proceed for Kashi. It is said that in the morning, except Shiva himself, no one else could get up so Lord Shiva set out for Kashi himself cursing the others to become stone images. As a result we have one less than a crore stone images and carvings at Unakoti. These carvings are located at a beautifully landscaped forest area with green vegetation all around which add to the beauty of the carvings. The images found at Unakoti are of two types, namely rock-carved figures and stone images.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/north-east-india-paradise-on-earth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Incredible India &#8211; Tourism In India</title>
		<link>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/incredible-india-tourism-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/incredible-india-tourism-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 16:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/?p=654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India is a country that attracts millions of tourists every year and is considered one of the most popular tourist destinations in the world. These visitors are attracted to its natural beauty and cultural heritage. It has many historic sites as well like the Taj Mahal, Golden Temple, Red Fort, etc. With so much to &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/incredible-india-tourism-in-india/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Incredible India &#8211; Tourism In India</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>India is a country that attracts millions of tourists every year and is considered one of the most popular tourist destinations in the world. These visitors are attracted to its natural beauty and cultural heritage. It has many historic sites as well like the Taj Mahal, Golden Temple, Red Fort, etc. With so much to offer, it’s no surprise that tourism is one of the main sources of revenue for the country!&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tourism in India has been seen as a major tool to bring about socio-economic development to the people of the country. India’s tourism industry has grown steadily in recent years. Not only this, India Tourism industry also provides employment opportunities to several people from all parts of the world. There are ample numbers of hotels, resorts, food joints and various other amenities available for tourists arriving in India.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No wonder Tourism is an important foreign exchange earner for India. The Department of Tourism, Ministry of Civil Aviation, Government of India is the apex body for the largest development and promotion of Indian tourism. To promote tourism in India, the government has been implementing a number of campaigns and schemes. These include Incredible India campaign along with a number of planned events such as the International Travel Mart, Destination India Exhibitions worldwide and Indian Cultural Festivals Abroad to attract foreign tourists.</p>



<p>India is a vast country with a lot to offer. Therefore, it comes as no surprise that millions of people pay India a visit every year. The country offers a variety of sights and sounds to enjoy, from the vibrant cities to the peaceful countryside. With its diversity of tourist attractions, India is also known for yoga and meditation. From the snow-capped Himalayas to the tropical beaches of Goa, from the wildlife of Assam to the largest tea field of Kerala, there is something new in every corner of this country. Moreover, with major cities such as Mumbai, Bangalore, Chandigarh, and Delhi being so well connected by air, road, and rail networks from across the globe, it’s easy to get around and explore some of the most iconic landmarks in India.</p>



<p>A country with a rich and colourful history, India is home to some of the world’s most fascinating cultures. India is a country located in South Asia and the capital of India is New Delhi. The Government of India, the Constitutional Republic represents a highly diverse population of thousands of ethnic groups and the many languages spoken in the country.</p>



<p>According to the Population Reference Bureau (PRB), it has a population of over 1.2 billion, making it the second-most populous country in the world. Built-in approximately 9,000 years ago, India was largely self-contained and became a cultural arena associated with Hinduism. The roots of this tradition can be traced to the Indus civilization.</p>



<p>Other religions such as Buddhism and Jainism originated in India, where Buddhism spread throughout Asia, while both religions are quite popular in the subcontinent. India has also developed a rich intellectual life in such fields as astronomy, fine art, architecture, mathematics, and music.</p>



<p>The country has been recognized for its economic development since gaining independence in 1947. It has become the seventh-largest country in the world, and it is geographically distinct from other Asian nations because of its location between mountains and the sea. India is a country of many contrasts, from the Indian Ocean to snow-capped peaks and the deserts in Rajasthan to the green forests of Kerala.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/incredible-india-tourism-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Offbeat Places To Visit</title>
		<link>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/5-offbeat-places-to-visit/</link>
					<comments>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/5-offbeat-places-to-visit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 16:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/?p=639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tired of the known tourist trails? Seeking to get away to a new place? The offbeat destinations in India offer an awesome experience. Escape the hustle-bustle of cities and indulge in incredible experiences. Vacations in these lesser-known locales of the country are truly memorable. Here is a list of 5 offbeat destinations in India that &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/5-offbeat-places-to-visit/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">5 Offbeat Places To Visit</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tired of the known tourist trails? Seeking to get away to a new place? The offbeat destinations in India offer an awesome experience. Escape the hustle-bustle of cities and indulge in incredible experiences. Vacations in these lesser-known locales of the country are truly memorable. Here is a list of 5 offbeat destinations in India that are known for an awesome experience:</p>



<p><strong>1. Mawlynnong, Meghalaya</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/meg1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-642" width="709" height="381" srcset="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/meg1.jpg 1023w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/meg1-300x161.jpg 300w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/meg1-768x413.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 709px) 100vw, 709px" /></figure>



<p>Mawlynnong in&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/meghalaya/">Meghalaya</a></strong>, is one of the must visit offbeat places in India. Blessed with the charm of North East India, Mawlynnong has been awarded as the cleanest village in Asia in 2003. The eco-friendly village community will give you some amazing lessons on life.</p>



<p>The scenic bliss of the town is refreshing for your senses. There are waterfalls to visit, caves to explore and most importantly walk on the Living Roots Bridge. Created out of the roots of the trees, the bridges are truly a wonder. Don’t’ stop at just this town, backpack throughout Meghalaya.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>2. Halebid, Karnataka</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/hal1-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-645" width="721" height="541" srcset="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/hal1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/hal1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/hal1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/hal1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/hal1-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 721px) 100vw, 721px" /></figure>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/halebid/">Halebid</a></strong>&nbsp;in Karnataka is one of the ancient temple towns of South India. The town is untouched by tourist crowds, therefore a beautiful offbeat experience. Known as Dwarasamudra, gateway to the seas, Halebid is the capital of the Hoysala Dynasty for about 150 years.</p>



<p>Sacked by the armies of Malik Kafur in the early 14th century, the town fell into a state of ruin. Even in the ravaged state, the town’s glory still remains undiminished. Spend time exploring the temple ruins of Halebid. You can also combine your tour with a visit to Belur along with Jain monuments at Shravanabelagola.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>3. Ziro, Arunachal Pradesh</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/zir1-1024x640.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-649" width="743" height="465" srcset="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/zir1-1024x640.jpg 1024w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/zir1-300x188.jpg 300w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/zir1-768x480.jpg 768w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/zir1-1536x960.jpg 1536w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/zir1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 743px) 100vw, 743px" /></figure>



<p>One of the most beautiful places in&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/arunachal-pradesh/">Arunachal Pradesh</a></strong>, Ziro is blessed with beauty, bliss and incredible experiences. Away from the touristy trails,<strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/ziro/">Ziro</a></strong>&nbsp;is among the beautiful offbeat destinations in India. Puffy white clouds float in the horizon. Beautiful green patches and rice fields are visible as far as the eye can see. ion addition, the Apatani tribe welcomes you with their friendly smiles and you would love to know their way of life. The&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/fairs-and-festivals/arunachal-pradesh/ziro-festival-of-music.html">Ziro music festival</a></strong>&nbsp;is a great time to visit. Don’t just visit Ziro stay there as a local.</p>



<p><strong>4. Patan, Gujrat</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/pat1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-650" width="749" height="500" srcset="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/pat1.jpg 910w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/pat1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/pat1-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></figure>



<p>One of the newest addition to India’s UNESCO World Heritage Sites,&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/patan/">Patan</a></strong>&nbsp;in&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/gujarat/">Gujarat</a></strong>&nbsp;will make for a lovely offbeat holiday places to travel to. Dating back to 745 AD, Patan, the former capital of the Chandva Rulers is dotted with lovely temples, lakes, and beautiful step walls. Ran Ki Vav being the most prominent one. Built in the 11th century, this grand step-well of Maru-Gurjara architectural style is designed as an inverted temple as obeisance to life-giving water. Patan is quite famous for Patola sarees, one of the finest hand-made textiles in the world.</p>



<p><strong>5. Chopta, Uttarakhand</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/cho1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-651" width="771" height="491" srcset="https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/cho1.jpg 1000w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/cho1-300x191.jpg 300w, https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/cho1-768x489.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 771px) 100vw, 771px" /></figure>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/tourist-attraction/uttaranchal/hill-stations-in-uttaranchal/chopta.html">Chopta</a></strong>&nbsp;is a scenic hill station in&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/uttaranchal/">Uttarakhand</a></strong>. In contrast to the tourist crowded hill towns, Chopta is relatively unknown. Watch the snow-covered peaks in the backdrop. The green slopes and grassy meadows have a relaxed vibe. It is certainly a perfect spot to take a break from the city life. Enjoy the lesser pleasures of life in the picturesque town. If you are keen on adventure then Chopta serves as a base to trek to Tungnath temple and the&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.indianholiday.com/wildlife-india/kedarnath-sanctuary.html">Kedarnath wildlife sanctuary</a></strong>. You can also trek to Chandrashila peak. Enjoy natural bliss on your offbeat holiday in Uttarakhand.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://srijitchakroborty.github.io/wordpress4/5-offbeat-places-to-visit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
